亲爱的亲爱的 快看快看
Honey, honey, look, look.
她下巴又开始乱动了
She's doing that thing with her jaw again.
可怜的孩子 她给自己太大压力了
Poor kid. She puts so much pressure on herself.
这是强迫性神经失调
It's an obsessive-compulsive thing.
我看了不下一百篇相关论文了
I have read like 100 articles about it.
她到底是怎么得上这病的
Where does she get it from?
这很难说
Yeah, it's -- it's a mystery.
我知道
I know.
艾丽克斯
Alex...
宝贝 理我一下
Honey, hi! Hi, hi, hi.
休息一下怎么样
Why don't you take a little break?
妈 明天早上就要考试了
Mom, the test is tomorrow morning.
我一刻也不能休息
I'm not taking any breaks.
就一小会 好吧
Just a little -- oh, okay.
她每隔六秒下巴就动一下
She does that jaw thing every six seconds.
就像迷你高尔夫场的河马一样
It's like the hippopotamus at the miniature-golf place.
我的球总是被那些河马巨大的牙齿弹回来
Ohh, I've bounced so many balls off those big teeth.
时机最重要
It's all about the timing!
卢克
Luke!
就差一点
So close!
-你个白痴别闹了 -卢克 回你房间去
- Stop it, you idiot! - Hey, hey, Luke, go to your room.
快点
Go on!
她必须吃点东西
She's got to eat.
-我出于爱她才给她吃的 -快回房去
- I did it out of love. - Go.
瞧她拿着小口琴的样子
Look at her with the little harmonica.
是啊 她就像个小朱尼尔·韦尔斯一样
I know. She's like a little junior Junior Wells.
你在哪买的口琴啊
Where did you buy it for her?
我以为是你买给她的
I thought you got it for her.
坏了 小卡 她肯定是从刚才那家店顺手拿的
Oh, no. Cam, she must have grabbed it from that store.
好吧 宝宝
Okay. Honey...
听好了 偷东西是不对的
listen. Stealing is wrong.
我们必须马上回去把钱付给人家
Now, we have to go back and pay for it.
小卡 那家店很远唉
Cam, it's so far away.
没事 我也没真打算回去
No,I'm not going back there.
翠西
Tracy?
天啊 是你啊 米奇尔
Oh, my god. Mitchell.
这位是卡梅隆 我的伴侣
Uh, this is -- this is Cameron, my partner...
这是我们的女儿莉莉
Oh. And, uh, our daughter, Lily.
小卡 这位是 这位是翠西
Oh, Cam, this is -- this is Tracy.
就是你之前提过的那位翠西啊
Oh. "Tracy" Tracy.
-是的 -久仰大名
- Yes. - Oh, hi.
翠西是我高中时的女朋友
Tracy was my high-school girlfriend.
千真万确哦
Yes. Yes, it's true.
我交过女朋友 事实上还不止一个
I had girlfriends -- quite a few, actually.
我也带过不少女生去鸡舍呢
I, too, took my fair share of ladies to the hen house.
真的就是鸡舍
Literally,
我带她们去养鸡的地方
I did take them to the hen house.
那可是农场里
That's the only place
唯一能有点隐私的地方
you could get some privacy on a farm.
真的吗
Really?
那些 那些女孩叫什么
What were these -- what were these girls' names?
有奈丽·福布什
Oh, well, there was Nellie Forbush...
贝蒂·里佐
Betty Rizzo...
-艾丽莎 -杜利特尔
- Eliza... - Doolittle.
这些都是音乐剧人物的名字
These are characters from musicals.
你太基了
You're so gay,
你都想不出个女生的名字
you can't even think of real girls' names.
金·麦卡非 这可是个真名字
Kim Mcafee -- that's a real one.
这是《再见，伯迪》里面的
"Bye Bye Birdie."
你最近怎么样
What's new?
我去年结婚了
I got married last year.
太棒了
Th-that's great.
你打算在城里待多久
How long are you in town for?
就待个两三天 我们现在住我父母家
Just a couple of days. We're staying at my folks'.
我太想知道米奇尔高中时是啥样的了
Oh, I want to hear all about Mitchell from high school.
那时他有胡子吗
Did he have a beard?
他现在跟那时一样 没怎么变
Uh, you're looking at her.
当然我那时不知道他喜欢男生
Of course I didn't know it back then.
不过我们应该
But we should -- we should all
一起出来聚聚
we should all hang out.
还是算了吧
Uh...no.
保重
W-well, take care.
好的
Okay.
再见
Bye.
瞧她那冷冰冰的表情
Thumpety thump-thump. Look at frosty go!
是有点奇怪
That was weird.
别想哪么多了 都是高中的事了
Well, don't worry about it. It's high school, honey.
-实际上 -怎么了
- Well, actually... - What?
毕业十周年聚会上 我们有点喝多了
At our 10-year reunion, we got a little drunk,
于是开始追忆往事 结果不知不觉就
started reminiscing, one thing led to another...
难道你又变直了
You went back?
我只是想看看我能不能做到
I-I think I just wanted to see if I could.
结果我还真可以
Turns out I could.
这事儿在哪发生的
Where did this happen?!
在校医室
Um, in the nurse's office.
我耳边现在还响着纸张的卷缩声
I can still hear the crinkling of the paper.
在那之后我一直没回过她电话
After that, I-I didn't return any of her phone calls,
也没再见过她
and I haven't seen her since.
你这个小坏蛋
You naughty little girl.
没办法 可可利口酒喝多了
Well, you know, that's what happens
我就会这样
when you give me Kahlua.
喂
Hello.
杰 猜猜刚才谁打电话来了
Jay, guess who called.
-霍夫曼一家 -谁
- The hoffmans. - Who?
没错
That's right.
就是我们在卡波的酒店酒吧里认识的那家人
The ones from the hotel bar in Cabo.
他们今晚进城过夜 想一跟咱们起吃个晚饭
They're in town for the night. They want to go to dinner.
该死 是那个无趣男和那个大嗓门吗
Oh, hell. The boring guy and the loudmouth?
就是 接到他们的电话我超开心
I know. I was so excited that they called.
我不想见他们
I don't want to see them.
就是 他们太好玩了
I know! So much fun!
你正和他们在一起吧
You're with them right now, aren't you?
是啊
Yes! Ha ha.
他们也迫不及待想见你呢
And they can't wait to see you, too!
好了 把笔放下 你必须休息一下
Okay, pencils down. You're taking a break.
不行 我可不能休息
No, I-I can't afford to take a break.
桑杰·帕特尔也没休息
Sanjay patel's not taking a break.
显然桑杰的父母不关心他
Well, obviously, Sanjay's parents don't care about him.
或是"她"
Or "her".
桑杰是个什么破名字啊
What is that -- "Sanjay"?
桑杰是全班
Sanjay's the only one in class
唯一可能超过我的人
who might do better than me,
我绝对不允许这件事发生
and I cannot let that happen.
宝贝 听听你说的话
Honey, listen to yourself.
这心态可不健康
It's just not healthy.
都是我的错
This is my fault.
你看到我如此优异
You see me achieve excellence,
所以压力才会很大
and it puts a lot of pressure on you.
那我呢
What about me?
不好意思
Sorry. Yeah.
我的优异让你们两个都有很大压力
It puts a lot of pressure on both of you.
谢谢你 菲尔
Thanks, Phil.
-好了 走吧 我们找点乐子去 -不要
- Okay, come on. Let's go have some fun! - No!
走吧
Let's go!
没错
Yes!
这感觉不错吧 宝贝儿
Doesn't this feel good, sweetheart?
好玩吧
It's fun, right?
说实在的 我觉得你太过担心莉莉了
Honestly, I think you're overly worried about Lily.
又不是说她长大后就会变成贼
It's not like she's gonna grow up to be a thief.
再说 最重要的是
And besides, at the end of the day,
她的行为准则是跟谁学的
who does she learn her behavior from?
我们
Us.
我们是她的楷模
We're her role models.
就像我妈常说的那样
Like mama always said,
我们的孩子就是我们的迷你版本
our children are just miniature versions of us.
-走吧 -小卡
- Come on. - Cam.
来嘛 杰
Oh, come on, Jay.
给姐笑个
Give me one smile.
我知道你很开心的
I know you want to.
来嘛 杰 给姐笑个 我知道你很开心的
Oh, come on, Jay. Give me one smile. I know you want to.
这个好玩吧 杰
Isn't that fun, Jay?
咱们聚在一起真是太好了
Oh, this has been so much fun!
听到你这么说 我很惊讶呢
You know, I'm surprised to hear you say that.
你今晚一直都很沉默呢
You've been pretty quiet.
那是因为我是个聆听者
That's because I'm a listener.
我喜欢聆听
I love to listen.
这是我的爱好
It's my hobby.
聆听是你的爱好吗
Listening is your hobby?
当然
Sure.
你们一定要过来拜访我们
You guys have got to come out and visit us.
说真的 你们可不能拒绝
Seriously. We're not taking no for an answer.
没错 没错 没错
Yes. Yes, yes.
-我们非常愿意 -好吧 咱慢慢来
- Oh, we would love to! - Okay, let's slow down.
你们是很好的人
You're nice people.
我们也是很好的人
We're nice people.
但是 说实在的
But let's be honest --
我们都在尝试着
we've all tried to do that thing
逼自己认为咱们是朋友
where we force a friendship
但实际上咱们并不是
that isn't really there.
所以咱们何不就此结束这一切
So why don't we just call it a day right now
相互道再见 握个手
and say goodbye, shake hands,
祝愿每个人幸福安康
wish each other well?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
这太尴尬了
This is so uncomfortable.
不 不 这件事好就好在
No, no, but the beauty of it is
我们以后永远都不会再见面了
we're never gonna see each other again,
所以 也用不着感到尴尬
so there's no reason to be uncomfortable.
他们今晚住咱们家
They're staying with us tonight.
他们的行李还在咱家呢
Their bags are in our house.
那么你说对了
Oh, then you were right.
这的确很尴尬
This is uncomfortable.
好吃吗
Do you like it?
做这道菜的时候需要加一杯水
The recipe called for a cup of water,
但是我用牛奶替代了 这样酱汁更粘稠
but I used milk instead to make the sauce creamier.
小卡 我要跟你说件事
Cam, I need to tell you something.
你讨厌这道菜
You hate it.
-卡梅隆 -不
- Cameron. - No.
你是对的 我永远都不该尝试新的东西
You're right. I shouldn't try anything new ever.
别闹了 我要跟你说正事
Stop it. I'm trying to talk to you.
是这样的 今天
Okay, today,
当我们离开百货商场的时候
when we were leaving the mall,
我看到翠西在喷泉旁
I saw Tracy by the fountain --
不要告诉我你又跟她睡了
Please, don't tell me you slept with her again.
有吗 没有吧 对吧
Did you? You didn't. Right?
你在开玩笑
You're joking.
是的
Yeah.
好吧
Okay. Um...
我不知道该怎么开口 我都不知道我猜的对不对
I don't know how to say this, or -- or if I'm even right.
也许是我猜错了
I'm probably not.
但是 她跟一个大概八岁左右的
But, um, she was with a redheaded boy,
红头发的小男孩在一起
about 8 years old,
自从我们俩那个以后 也差不多过了八年
which is the same number of years since we...
不
No!
而她说 她结婚才一年
And she said she'd only been married a year,
而这正好说明了
and it would explain why
她见到我为什么会那么别扭
she was so awkward with me, and --
不
No.
我知道 我知道 这很疯狂
I know. I know. It's crazy,
但是 小卡 我必须搞清楚他是不是我儿子
but, Cam, I need to find out if he's mine.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
是的 你不能跟你的伴侣说
Yeah. Yeah, well, you don't just tell your partner
你或许跟其他人有了孩子
you may have a baby with someone else
然后还指望他能
and expect him to go back to eating
像什么事都没发生过一样
a delicious and inventive meal
继续吃这顿美味且独创的佳肴
like it's nothing!
我明白 小卡 可就算他真是我儿子
Okay, Cam, but even if he is mine,
咱俩之间也不会有任何改变
it doesn't change anything between us.
米奇尔 你必须得让我消化一下
Mitchell, I need to have my reaction.
杰
Jay!
他们叫了一辆出租车 你现在满意了吗
They order a cab. Are you happy now?
当我听到关车门的声音才会满意
I'll be happy when I hear a trunk close.
妈妈 你要喝杯水吗
Hey, mom. You want a drink of water?
不 小可爱 现在不要
No, pape. Not right now.
你确定吗 你看起来很渴
You sure? You look thirsty.
你今天是怎么了 老叫我喝水
What's with you and the water today?
这是一个滴水杯
It's a dribble cup.
用它喝水肯定会漏
You can't drink from it without spilling.
我觉得这会让我很受欢迎
I think it's going to make me very popular.
小可爱 你为啥要用这些东西
Ay, pape, why do you need these things
来让你受欢迎呢
to make you popular?
先是拐杖
First the walking stick,
-然后又是名片的 -他们走了吗
- then the business cards. - Are they gone yet?
你为何要跟他们说那种话
Why did you talk to them like that?
怎么了 我不过是实话实说罢了
What? I was just being honest.
他们无聊得要死
They're boring as hell!
小声点 他们会听到的
Quiet! They can hear you!
他或许已经听到了
Oh, he probably already heard me.
他的兴趣就是聆听嘛
His hobby is listening.
杰 你不能这样对待别人
Jay, you don't treat people like that.
怎么 难道要我像你一样吗
What? I should do what you do?
假装喜欢那些你并不喜欢的人
Pretend to like someone you don't?
我现在就在假装喜欢你
I'm doing it right now.
这么说吧 歌洛莉亚
Can I tell you something, Gloria?
当你到了一定年纪
When you reach a certain age,
你就会想把你余下的这点宝贵的时间
you want to spend what precious little time you have left
花在那些你真正喜欢的人身上
with people you actually like,
而不是那些想从你这得到什么的混蛋身上
not some bozos who glommed onto you.
深有同感
Tell me about it.
有一个五年级的总粘着我 甩都甩不掉
I've got a clingy fifth grader I can't shake.
瞧见了没 连曼尼都知道
See, even Manny knows.
我支持你 杰 渴了吗
I got your back, Jay. Thirsty?
曼尼 去睡觉
Manny, go to sleep.
我们能不能别再提这事了
Can we just please forget about this now?
最过分的是
And the worst thing
你都不警告我一下 就把我给卖了
is that you sold me out without warning
让我像个傻瓜一样
and made me look like a fool.
夫妇间应该互相帮助
Husband and wife are supposed to help each other,
而不是把对方往火坑里推
not throw each other under the bus!
我就绝不会那样对你
I would never do that to you!
歌洛莉亚 歌洛莉亚 等等
Gloria -- Gloria, wait!
帮我拿一下书好吗 我把它落在楼下了
Could you get my book for me? I left it downstairs.
你来了
There you are.
我们的计程车到了
Our cab is here.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
不是你的错 那就再见了
Not your fault. Well, goodbye.
等一下 你们忘了拿这个
Ay, wait. You left this.
不 那是送给你的
Oh, no, that's...for you.
在卡波你说过自己是
In Cabo, you mentioned you were a fan
加夫列尔·加西亚·马尔克斯的粉丝
of Gabriel García Márquez.
所以我们找到他
So, we tracked him down
让他在《百年孤独》一书上
and got him to sign a copy
为你签名
of "One Hundred Years of Solitude" for you.
这礼物太珍贵了
That's amazing.
我们走了
Well...
不 不 别走
No, no. Don't go.
我真的想留你们在这过夜
I really want you to spend the night here.
杰显然不这么想
Jay clearly doesn't.
杰不知道自己想要什么
Jay doesn't know what he wants.
虽然我不愿跟别人提起这事 不过
I don't like to tell this to people, but, uh...
杰的脑子已经 不太好使了
Jay's mind is...going away.
-天哪 -不会吧
- Oh, my god. - No.
他年事已高 好几个夜晚我甚至感觉
He's so old, some nights it's like...
他的神智都不怎么清楚了
he's not even here.
歌洛莉亚 亲爱的
Gloria, honey.
就这么定了 我们哪都不去了
That's it. We're not going anywhere.
过来
Come on.
你昨晚没上床睡觉
You never came to bed.
我在书房睡着了
I fell asleep in the den.
小卡 我们得谈谈
Cam, we need to talk about --
米奇尔 等等
Mitchell, wait.
听着
Listen.
我彻夜未眠 思前想后
I was up all night, thinking about it.
得出的结论是
And here's the thing.
如果十年前你告诉我
If you would have told me 10 years ago
有朝一日我会和某人共同生活
that I would be living with someone
并一起养育一个漂亮的小女孩
and raising a beautiful baby girl,
我会说你疯了
I would have said you were crazy.
但现在这一切都成了事实
But here we are.
你和莉莉是我生命中
And you and Lily are the best things
最美好的东西
that have ever happened to me.
所以如果你说还有一个孩子
So if you're telling me there's another kid,
那只能是件好事了 对吧
how can that be anything but good?
小卡 我太 我太
Oh, Cam, that's -- that means so --
不 没事的
No, it's okay.
不 我必须释放一下情感
No, I need to have my reaction.
我们会没事的
We're gonna be okay.
那我们现在该怎么办
So what do we do now?
不知道 我想我应该
I don't know. I guess I'm gonna have to --
我应该打个电话给翠西
I'm gonna have to call Tracy
跟她说我们得谈谈
and tell her that we need to talk.
好吧
Okay.
-你紧张吗 -我快吓死了
- Are you nervous? - I'm terrified.
我是说 这孩子会怎么想我
Yes. I mean, what's this kid gonna think of me?
他人生最初的八年我都不在身边
I've been absent for the first eight years of his life.
该如何弥补这一段时间
I mean, how do you make up for time like that when --
好 你先冷静下来
Okay, slow down.
你想太多了
You're spinning out.
也许这一切都只是咱俩在瞎想
It's probably just a false alarm.
你说得对
No, you're right.
可能跟我上次以为自己要秃了那次一样
This could be my "going bald" scare all over again.
是啊 咱都知道那事的最终结果
Yeah. And we know how that turned out.
亲爱的
Honey.
如果世上最伟大的科学家们联手促成
What would happen if the greatest scientists on earth
两大最凶猛食肉动物的交配会怎么样
got together to mate nature's two most violent predators?
你是在说"蓝环章鱼"3D版吗
Are we talking about "Croctopus" in 3D?
两张十美元
At 2 10.
速度出手
Book it!
克莱尔和我热衷于淘便宜电影票
Claire and I share a true love of cheesy cinema.
我们喜欢的影片类型有
Um, our favorite categories
基因处理后失控的生物
include genetically engineered animals gone wrong...
交换肉身的老者与少年
Old and young people switching bodies.
艰苦养育孩子的人们
Uh, tough guys taking care of babies.
出过3部以上续集的任何一部电影
Any sequel three and higher.
没错
Oh, yeah.
通常新片的入手价在一张五美元左右
Usually get a new cast around five --
这才是亮点
That's where the magic really happens.
亲爱的 考试成绩怎么样
Hey, honey, how'd your test go?
全班第二
Second highest in the class.
不错啊
Well, that's great.
桑杰·帕特尔比我高十二分
Sanjay Patel edged me out by 12 points.
-亲爱的 谁在乎那丫头考几分 -是个小子
- Oh, honey, who cares what she did? - It's a he!
桑杰是个很普通的印度男孩名
Sanjay is a very common Indian boy's name.
叫这名字的有上百万人呢
There are like millions of them.
宝贝 你还是考得很好
Sweetheart, it's still a great score.
你对自己别太苛刻了
I hope you're not beating yourself up.
-我没有 -那才是我们的好孩子
- I'm not. - That's our girl.
桑杰的爸爸是外科医生 妈妈是教授
Sanjay's dad's a surgeon. His mom's a professor.
这我可没法比
I can't compete with that.
我只能根据自家情况
I'll just have to do the best I can
竭尽全力
with what I was given.
好孩子
Good for you!
亲爱的 我们为你骄傲
We're proud of you, honey.
她真是个好孩子
She's such a good kid.
是啊
Yeah, she is.
她是不是说只能
Did she just say she was gonna do the best
根据自家情况竭尽全力
with what she was given?
不知道啊 我还在想有那么多人叫桑杰
I don't know. I was still thinking about all the Sanjays.
我却一个也不认识 但我认识三个叫米尔顿的
I don't know any, but I know three Miltons.
她是在嫌我们笨
She's saying we're stupid!
那她就错了
Well, she's...wrong.
真的吗
Is she?
亲爱的 你看咱俩过了多久
Honey, look at how long it just took us
才明白她是在损我们
to figure out that she's insulting us.
我们给孩子拖后腿了吗
Are we holding our kids back?
才没呢 咱俩都挺聪明的
No. We're both bright people.
咱俩都是大学毕业 爱看书
We're college graduates. We read.
我觉得我可以肯定地说
I'd go so far as to say
咱俩的智慧和阅历就跟
we're as intellectual and sophisticated as --
太棒了 “蓝环章鱼”的票到手了
Sweet! "Croctopus" tickets confirmed!
我只是觉得应该我们应该提议带曼尼去玩玩
Oh, I just think that we should offer to take Manny.
也许一起过个周末之类的
Maybe for a weekend. Something.
大家好啊
Hey, guys.
-曼尼好啊 -你好啊曼尼
- Oh, hey, Manny. - Hey, Manny.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去上高尔夫球课
Got a golf lesson.
我的挥击太烂了
My swing's a mess.
曼尼和我一起去
Manny's coming with me.
不行 你现在不能下楼
No, you can't go downstairs now.
你会撞见霍夫曼夫妇的
You'll run into the Hoffmans.
其实 我也想跟他们谈谈
Actually, I want to talk to them,
因为我一直在想
because I've been thinking about
你昨晚说的话
what you said last night,
我很抱歉让你难堪了
and I'm sorry if I embarrassed you.
你是对的
You're right.
你永远不会对我做那样的事
You never would have done that to me.
-我原谅你了 -所以我要去跟他们道个别
- I forgive you! - So I'll say goodbye.
杰 不要去
No, Jay.
别去
Don't do that.
一开始他们以为你喜欢他们
First they think you like them.
然后又觉得你不喜欢他们
Then they think you don't like them.
别把他们搞糊涂了
Don't confuse them.
我想为你做这件事
I want to do this for you.
杰 等一下
Jay, wait!
没关系的
It's okay.
杰 等一下
Ay, Jay, wait!
那么 你是 你是怎么做到的呢
So, hey, how -- how are you handling things,
我是说 和杰相处
you know, with Jay?
什么意思
What do you mean?
亲爱的 你妈妈跟我们说了
Honey, your mom told us
杰的情况 我是说
that Jay's, you know,
他状态有点不太好
a little off his game.
哪止一点呀 简直不能看
A little? It's hard to watch.
那他一定很沮丧
It must be so frustrating for him.
他的确经常骂人
Well, he does swear a lot.
最糟糕的是当他跑进树林的时候
You know, the worst is when he goes off into the woods.
还有 当他开车的时候
Oh, and when he drives --
我的天呐 真得小心
Oh, my god. Look out.
我很惊讶他到现在还没撞死过人
I'm surprised he hasn't killed anybody yet!
太好了 你们还在
I'm so glad you guys are still here.
我只是想说
I just want to say...
昨晚很抱歉
sorry for last night.
没关系的
It's okay.
我们理解
We understand.
你看 问题解决了吧
Ay, you see? Problem is solved.
走吧 你要迟到了
Now go. You're going to be late.
你们都没有错
There's nothing wrong with you guys.
错的是我
You know, it's -- it's me.
我们知道
Oh, we know.
斯蒂芬的父亲也有过同样的经历 我们能了解
We went through the same thing with Steph's father.
现在我有点懵了
Now I'm confused.
我是斯蒂芬
I'm Steph.
杰 拿着 我给你倒了一杯橙汁
Uh, here, Jay. I poured you a glass of orange juice.
谢谢你 孩子
Thanks, kid.
怎么回事 我到底是怎么了
What the hell? What's wrong with me?!
这总是很好玩
It's always funny.
杰 去换衣服吧
Jay, go change.
我一会就上来
I'll be there in one second.
也许我们也该出发了
Maybe we should get going.
那至少让我载你们去机场吧
Well, at least let me drive you to the airport.
-不不不不不 -不不不不不
- No, no. No, no, no. - Oh, no, no, no.
我们叫出租车就好
We'll call a cab.
亲爱的 你要吃爆米花什么的吗
Honey, do you want popcorn or anything?
不用 我不想吃
No, I'm good...
再说我自己带了不少吃的呢
'n' plenty.
水也不用买
So hold your water
而且我还在袖子里藏了些特趣巧克力
'cause I've got some "Twix" up my sleeve.
也许你很厉害
You may be cool,
但是我包里有饮料
but I'm...wine cooler.
咱俩真是绝配
I love us.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好啊 邓菲
Well, hello, Dunphy!
-那是谁 -是帕特尔夫妇
- Who is that? - It's the Patels,
桑杰的父母
Sanjay's parents.
最近好吧
Hey. Hey, how are you?
我听说桑杰今天考得相当好
I heard Sanjay did so well on his test today.
是的 我们都引以为傲
Oh, yes, we're very proud of him.
确实
Indeed.
你们是来看《两天的生活》的吗
Are you here to see "Deux jour de la vie"?
我们可不是来看《蓝环章鱼》的
Well, we're not here to see "Croctopus"!
如果你听见韦什的抱怨请不要见怪
Forgive Vish if you hear him groan.
他一看见译错的字幕就来气
He gets annoyed if the subtitles are mistranslated.
看来咱俩一样呀
Well, that makes "Deux" of us.
那一会儿 电影院里见了
I guess we'll...see you in there.
-没问题 -当然
- All right. - You bet.
待会见了
See you in there!
菲尔 你去哪啊
Phil, where are you going?!
看"蓝环章鱼"啊
"Croctopus."
亲爱的 亲爱的
Honey. Honey!
我觉得我们应该去看这部电影
I think we should go see this movie.
我为什么非得看一部法国电影呢
Why do I have to watch a French movie?
我又没做错事
I didn't do anything wrong.
也许艾丽克斯说的对
Well, maybe Alex has a point.
要是咱俩一点求知欲都没有的话
How can we encourage our kids
又怎么能激发
to have intellectual curiosity
孩子的求知欲呢
when we don't have any?
我不知道
I don't know.
反正只是占咱俩两小时而已
It's two hours of our life.
好吧
Fine.
为了我们的孩子
For our kids.
有时我真讨厌咱孩子
Sometimes I hate the kids.
我知道
I know.
我一点也看不懂
I'm so confused.
我看懂了
I'm not.
我喜欢这电影
I love this.
才不是呢
You do not.
那你说一个你喜欢的情节
Name one thing you've liked about this.
我喜欢有个老人在海滩上的那一幕
I liked the scene with the old man on the beach.
那是另一部电影的预告片
That was a trailer for a different movie.
也就是说那个老头不会再出现了吗
So he's not coming back?
没错 不会出现了
No, he's not coming back,
我也不会再出现了
and I'm not coming back, either!
我还在试着享受这部电影呢
Some of us are trying to enjoy this film.
当克莱尔在看一部
While Claire watched one of the most
受到年度最佳好评的电影时
highly acclaimed films of the year,
毫无教育意义可言的电影
with absolutely no redeeming value.
但是超好看
And it was awesome.
我的天呐
Oh, my god.
感觉就像墨汁真的溅到我身上了一样
It feels like I have ink on me!
亲爱的
Sweetheart...
怎么了
What?
-我的天呐 -亲爱的
- Oh, my god. - Honey...
我睡着了 错过了结局
I fell asleep. I missed it.
好了 我们回家吧
Yeah, let's go home.
我真不敢相信我睡着了 而你又走了
I can't believe I fell asleep and you left.
艾丽克斯说的对 咱俩就是白痴
Alex is right -- we're idiots.
克莱尔 别这样
Claire, stop it.
听着
Look...
我们的孩子是全班第二名
our kid got the second-best grade in the class.
傻瓜父母才养不出这么优秀的孩子
Dumb parents don't make kids that smart.
她遗传了我们俩最好的基因
She got the best of both of us.
想象一下
Kind of like if you combined
如果你创造了一种生物
the jaw strength of a crocodile
既有鳄鱼的嘴巴 还能像章鱼一样喷墨
and the ink-spraying capabilities of an octopus.
那一定是无法阻止的怪兽
You'd end up with something unstoppable.
可最后他们还是把他给灭了 不是吗
But they did stop him in the end, didn't they?
应该是"她" 她产了很多蛋
"Her". And she laid eggs.
-蓝环母章鱼 -没错
- Croctopi. - Yeah.
快看 天才在那干吗呢
Check out Einstein over there.
实在太可悲了
Well, that's just sad.
你好啊 韦什
Hey, Vish.
这样就行了
You just do this.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们喜欢这部电影吗
So, did you enjoy the film?
一点也不喜欢
Not in the least.
我觉得效果太二维了
I actually found it quite two-dimensional.
很高兴见到你
Well, lovely to see you.
也很高兴见到你们
Good to see you, too.
好了 先告辞了
All right. Bye.
再见
Bye.
请您先行 医生大人
After you, doctor.
请您先行 教授大人
After you, professor.
米奇尔 卡梅隆
Mitchell, Cameron.
进来吧
Come on in.
我们 我们得谈谈
Um, so...w-we need to talk.
谈什么
About what?
介意我们坐下聊吗
Do you mind if we sit down?
请坐
Please.
翠西 有件事我不吐不快
Um, Tracy, I...I have something to say,
我怕我要是不一次说完
and I'm afraid that if I just don't
就再也说不出口了
say it all at once, I'm never gonna say it.
所以
So...
这让我想起了舞会那晚
This takes me back to prom night.
再次声明 那晚实在抱歉
Again...sorry about that.
总而言之
Anyway, uh,
咱俩昨天在商场碰见之后
I saw you yesterday across the mall after we spoke
我注意到 你是和另一人一同来的
and couldn't help but notice that you weren't alone.
你当时和
Uh, you were with...
我真不知道该怎么启齿
I don't even know how to put this.
他叫波比
His name...is Bobby.
波比
Bobby.
真是个好名字
Such a lovely name.
翠西
Tracy...
他是不是
I-is he...
没错 米奇尔
Yes, Mitchell.
他是
He is.
天呐 好吧
Oh, my god. Oh -- okay.
你怎么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
米奇尔 你和我已经没有任何瓜葛了
Mitchell, you and I don't have a relationship anymore.
我在咱俩那次小小的
I called you after our little...
护士室之旅之后试过给你打电话
visit to the nurse's room.
可你却一个电话都没回给我
You never returned any of my calls.
我当时吓坏了 翠西 我
I-I was freaked out, Tracy, and I --
让我们抛弃过去
Hey, let's not rehash the past...
关注未来
...but rather, focus on the future.
对 对 没错 小卡和我
Yes, yes. Yes, Cam and I, um,
想知道你是否愿意让我们
want to know if you're open...to us...
让我们和波比认识下
getting to know Bobby.
我认为这不是个好主意
I don't think that's a very good idea.
好吧 我懂
Okay, I understand.
起初肯定会有点尴尬
No, it might be a little awkward at first,
可时间能改变一切
but I think after some time...
我们还给他买了礼物
We brought him a present.
给波比的吗
For Bobby?
求求你 我们只是
Please, we just --
我们真的很想见见他
we really just want to meet him.
好吧
Fine.
好了
Okay.
波比
Bobby?
你能出来一下吗
Could you come out here?
亲爱的 怎么了
Hey, honey. What's up?
我想介绍你跟米奇尔和卡梅隆认识一下
I wanted to introduce you to Mitchell and Cameron.
-这是我丈夫 -你好吗
- This is my husband. - Hey. How ya doin'?
你好吗 老兄
Hey, what's up, dude?
-你好吗 -很好
- How ya doin'? - Good.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
-你好 我叫卡梅隆 -你好
- Hi. Cameron. - Hi, there. Yeah.
你们是怎么认识翠西的
So, uh, how do you know Tracy?
这个 我们
Um, uh, how -- uh, we, um...
我是米奇尔毕业舞会时的女伴
Mitchell took me to the prom.
-毕业舞会 -对 毕业舞会
- The prom. - The prom.
红发帅哥啊
Oh, a redhead.
你对红发情有独钟啊 是吧
You really have a type, don't you?
他们给你买了个礼物
They got you a present?
这不算什么
Oh...it's not...
-你不必 -是我就不打开了
- You don't need to -- - I wouldn't even --
你不必
You don't...
"小小棒球手"
"Li'l slugger"?
我还是先走了 你们俩好好谈谈
I'm just gonna go and let you two catch up.
怎么样 喜欢吗
'Sup?
想不到你居然还跟女生上过床
I never realized that you ever had sex with a girl
实际上 我那时候还挺吃香的
I kind of got around back then, actually.
-不只一个吗 -那还用说
- More than one? - Please.
除了翠西 还有谁
Well, there was Tracy. Who else?
还有贝蒂·里佐
Uh, Betty Rizzo.
不记得她了
Don't remember her.
艾丽莎·杜利特尔
Eliza Doolittle?
-奈丽·福布什 -她们都是你同学吗
- Nellie Forbush? - These were classmates?
有些是学姐
Well, s-s-some were older.
有些是学妹
S-some were younger.
丽泽和格蕾特尔·崔普
Uh, Liesel and Gretel Von Trapp.
很明显是两姐妹 我口味太重了吗
Sisters, obviously -- too far?
我不是白痴
I'm not an idiot.
你成天到晚都在看《音乐之声》
You played that record night and day.
-你干吗编这种事骗我 -我只是
- Why would you tell me a thing like that? - I just...